Guide to the Jerry Tyler Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Jerry Tyler papers
1948-1973
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5553
5553-001
Tyler, Jerry,$d1911-2005
1.79 cubic feet 2 boxes
Transcripts, correspondence, and other material primarily relating to Jerry Tyler's radio broadcasts on behalf of organized labor and his union activities as well as ILWU history
Jerry Tyler became active in organized labor in the 1940s, and remained active throughout his career as a longshoreman. This activism led to his work as a radio broadcaster in 1948 when the Seattle CIO Industrial Union Council, for which Tyler was secretary, decided to start a radio program. Tyler also authored a number of books, focusing primarily on "pulp fiction" in the 1930s and on non-fiction later in his life.
This collection includes transcripts of radio broadcasts, correspondence, clippings and ephemera. The materials relate to Tyler's union activities.
Radio transcript series include: National Union Marine Cooks and Stewards, CIO (July 15, 1948-July 26, 1948); Maritime Union Scripts (August 5, 1948-February 21, 1949); Labor Radio Committee (February 28, 1949-June 8, 1950); Reports from Labor (April 25, 1950-October 19, 1950); International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America (June 5, 1950-June 8, 1950); and an untitled set from Astoria, Oregon (July 3, 1950-February 12, 1951). There are two correspondence files, one general (1944-1951) and the other "Radio Correspondence" (1949-1950); and a newspaper clippings file (1949-1951).
Subject materials gathered by Tyler on ILWU history and his role in it. Tyler was editor of such publications as "The Hook" newsletters for ILWU Local 19 (Seattle); and the ILWU Local 19's "Strike Bulletin" from the 1971-1972 Pacific Coast Longshore Strike. Subject files and news clippings relating to the 1971 Pacific Coast Waterfront Strike. Folders include clippings from the ILWU International's newspaper, "The Dispatcher" on various longshore topics, as well as correspondence relating to all of these matters as well as other longshore and popular news publications. The materials include letters to the editor to various publications on issues relating to maritime labor and working class issues as well as correspondence with The ILWU International Union's newspapers The Dispatcher on various issues and articles from "The Rusty Hook."
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington
Open to all users.
Source: Ronald E. Magden, 2008; Judy Johnson, 2016.
Labor$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bLocal 19 (Seattle, Wash; Longshoremen's Strike, 1971-1972; Stevedores$xLabor unions$zWashington (State); Strikes and lockouts$xStevedores$zWashington (State); Radio scripts; Business correspondence; Ephemera; Records (Documents); Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Tyler, Jerry,$d1911-2005$vArchives; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Washington (State); Seattle
- National Union Marine Cooks and Stewards, 1948 (Box 1)
- Maritime Unions Script, 1948 (Box 1)
- Labor Radio Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
- Reports from Labor, 1950 (Box 1)
- International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America, 1950 (Box 1)
- Untitled (Astoria), 1950-51 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 1)
- Radio Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
- Clippings, 1949-1951 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, undated; 1968 (Box 1)
- Labels, "Reports from Labor", undated (Box 1)
- Longshore Strike- Newspaper articles and Letters, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
- ILWU Local 19, "The Hook", 1965-1968, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- ILWU Local 19 Strike Bulletins, 1971 (Box 2)
- ILWU Local 19. "Strike Bulletin", "Rusty Hook", and various clippings and correspondence on longshore issues, 1969-1971 (Box 2)